-CURRICULUM VITAE-

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Name: ONG Wee Kai (WENG Weikai) (翁偉凱)

Address: 139 Rivervale Street, #12-768, Singapore 540139

Contact No.: +65 97856139 (Mobile) / +65 63847239 (Residential)

Personal Email: wkaio1985@gmail.com

Date of Birth: 14 November 1985

SUMMARY

I graduated from the National University of Singapore with a Bachelor of Laws (Honours) and have been a Singapore-qualified advocate and solicitor since 2011. I have had transactional experience at a leading Singapore law firm in the general banking and finance practice area. At present, I am a legal counsel with an international bank in Singapore, providing advice in the areas of corporate and trade finance, OTC derivatives and general contract and company law.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mar 2014 – Present <u>Mizuho Bank, Ltd.</u> ("Mizuho-SG")

Legal Counsel (Legal and Business Administration

Department)

Feb 2013 – Mar 2014 Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Singapore

Foreign Service Officer (International Organisations

Directorate, United Nations / Legal Issues)

Jan 2011 – Feb 2013 WongPartnership LLP

Legal Associate (Banking & Finance)

EXPERIENCE AND EXPERTISE

(Mizuho-SG)

1. Corporate and Trade Finance / OTC Derivatives Transaction / General Advisory

Acts as in-house counsel on a variety of general banking / corporate matters to ensure legal risks are minimised in the day-to-day operations of Mizuho-SG. This includes a) providing transaction specific advice (for syndicated and

bilateral financing), b) conducting training for Mizuho-SG employees, c) managing the appointment and instruction of external counsel, d) coordinating legal management policies with Mizuho-SG's Head Office in Japan, e) advising and implementing Mizuho-SG's policies on legal risk management, f) drafting, reviewing and negotiation of documentation for loans, accounts, OTC derivative transactions, trade financing, banker's guarantees, service agreements and g) drafting, reviewing and advising on corporate mandate documentation.

Work scope includes drafting, reviewing and negotiation of:

- o Revolving / Term Loan Agreement Templates for China (Suzhou Industrial Park), Singapore, India, Indonesia and Vietnam;
- Finance Documents in syndicated loans;
- o Trade Finance Documentation (Invoice Discounting, Receivables Purchase Financing, Silent Payment Guarantee Master Agreement, Banker's Acceptance Financing, Letters of Credit)
- o OTC Derivatives Documentation (ISDA 1992 and 2002 Master Agreements, EMTA Master Confirmation Agreements);
- o Global Master Securities Lending Agreements (GMSLA);
- o Derivative-embedded Loan Agreements;
- o SWIFT SCORE Agreements (to support corporate-to-bank communications via the SWIFT messaging system);
- o Facility Letters, Current Accounts & Deposits Terms and Conditions;
- o Service Agreements (including SaaS Agreements);
- o Confidentiality Agreements / Non-Disclosure Agreements;
- o Demand Guarantees, Standby Letters of Credit;
- o Corporate Mandate (board resolutions, shareholders' resolutions, power of attorney).

2. Regulatory

 Advises Mizuho-SG on its various regulatory obligations in collaboration with the Compliance division.

Significant projects include:

- Successful implementation of Mizuho-SG's Policies and Documentations in connection with the following Regulatory Areas:
 - Personal Data (Personal Data Protection Act 2012 (No. 26 of 2012),
 Statutes of the Republic of Singapore);
 - o FATCA;
 - o Sanctions, Anti-Money Laundering and Countering the Financing of Terrorism;
 - o Outsourcing (MAS Guidelines on Outsourcing).

3. New Products (ad-hoc)

Liaises with Mizuho-SG's product specialists, instructs external counsel and reviews documentation for new products and services by the Bank.

(WongPartnership LLP)

4. Transactional Banking and Finance

Main responsibilities include reviewing, drafting and advising on financing documents including facility agreements, shareholder loan agreements, security and quasi-security documents (including assignments, share charges, debentures, inter-creditor agreements, security trust deeds, guarantees, deeds of discharge, reassignments and release), board resolutions, legal opinions and registration of charges, satisfaction of charges, variation of charges with the Accounting & Corporate Regulatory Authority of Singapore.

Significant projects include:

- Acted as counsel to the manager of the Borrower (a Singapore-listed REIT) in two simultaneous transactions to refinance a S\$500 million term loan facility, in which the borrower obtained a S\$320 million term loan facility and S\$185 million term loan facility from two syndicates of four banks, which were parties to the original S\$500 million financing.
- Acted as lenders' counsel to effect a change in the security agent and the addition of a new borrower in a \$500 million trade financing transaction involving a pulp-producing conglomerate. This transaction involved coordinating with the exiting facility agent/ security agent, incoming facility agent/security agent, the lenders, the borrower, foreign counsel in Hong Kong, Cayman islands, Bermuda, Macau and Indonesia, drafting amendment

and restatement agreements to the security trust agreement, guarantee, as well as the drafting of new security to be provided by the new lender (based on security already provided by original borrower), commercial contracts and legal opinion.

- Acted as counsel of a Singapore-listed company in the partial repayment of two secured term loan facilities (A\$105 million and S\$320 million) which involves a partial discharge of mortgage for the SGD facility, and a security substitution exercise for the AUD facility in which the existing security given thereunder is discharged and substituted for security given under another A\$86 million facility involving the company.
- Acted as counsel for Standard Chartered Bank and Oversea-Chinese Banking Corporation, as mandated lead arrangers, in respect of the S\$100 million loan facility to Ying Li International Real Estate Ltd, the first significant Chongqing property developer to be listed in Singapore through its key subsidiary, Chongqing Yingli Real Estate Development Co Ltd, for the refinancing of certain debts of Ying Li and its subsidiaries.
- Acted as Singapore counsel to the Xstrata group of companies in relation to the working capital facility arrangements entered into between a Singapore-incorporated subsidiary and several Singapore-incorporated joint venture companies, which arrangements were documented in transaction documents governed under Singapore law.

(Ministry of Foreign Affairs, Singapore)

5. Foreign Policy & Government

- Oversaw United Nations ("UN") 6th Committee and work agenda with the Attorney-General's Chambers and other relevant agencies to monitor, analyse and formulate positions on the agenda items considered in the Committee
- Monitored developments, analyse and work with relevant agencies to formulate positions on the International Criminal Court, International Humanitarian Law, Responsibility to Protect, UN Convention against Corruption, and the UN Convention Against Transnational Organised Crime
- Oversaw Singapore's engagement with the International Committee of the Red Cross ("ICRC"), including the visit by the President of the ICRC to Singapore

 Managed Singapore's humanitarian relief contributions to UN agencies/ in response to UN Flash Appeals

- Worked with agencies to ensure Singapore's compliance of UN Security Council resolutions (except for sanctions related to counter-proliferation, DPRK and Iran)
- Monitored candidatures of other countries to international organisations. Work
 with external agencies to decide, propose and implement vote swap
 arrangements, as well as to lobby support for Singapore's candidatures to
 international organisations.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- Advocate and Solicitor, Supreme Court of Singapore (since August 2011)
- Singapore Institute of Legal Education
 - Part "B" of the Singapore Bar Examination 2010

EDUCATION BACKGROUND, ACHIEVEMENTS AND AWARDS

- National University of Singapore
 - Bachelor of Laws (Honours) (2010) (2:2)
- Fudan University Student Exchange Programme (2009)
 - Distinctions in Intellectual Property Law, Private International Law and Economic Law (courses conducted and examined in Chinese)
- Singapore Armed Forces, HQ Army Medical Services, 3rd Combat Support Hospital
 - Certificate of Service: Combat Medic (Outstanding Performance) (2006)
 - National Service Excellence Award (2016)
- Victoria Junior College
 - GCE "A" Levels (2003) (4 Distinctions, 3 Credits)
 - Scholastic Assessment Test ("SAT") I (Total: 1560/1600, Verbal: 800, Math: 760)
- Catholic High School
 - GCE "O" Levels (2001) (8 Distinctions, 2 Credits)
 - Service Awards (Student's Council & English Literary Drama & Debating Society) (2001)

- Tan Kiok Ngiap Memorial Award (Academic Award): Top in English Language (Sec 3) (2000)
- Community Involvement Award (2000)
- Singapore Youth Festival Central Judging Competition (Drama) Silver Award (2001) Gold Award (1999)
- Others
 - Kayaking Proficiency Personal Skill 1-Star and 2-Star Awards (2014)

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Written: English and Chinese (First language proficiency)

French (Intermediate)

Spoken: English and Mandarin (First language proficiency)

French (Basic)